<resources>
    <string-array name="bottle_spin_array">
        <item>My Bar</item>
        <item>Add to Bar</item>
        <item>Shopping List</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="drink_spin_array">
        <item>Favorites</item>
        <item>Makeable</item>
        <item>All A-Z</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="bottle_filter_array">
        <item>All</item>
        <item>Spirits</item>
        <item>Liqueurs</item>
        <item>Mixers</item>
        <item>Amari</item>
        <item>Wines</item>
        <item>Groceries</item>
        <item>Flavorings</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="drink_filter_array">
        <item>All</item>
        <item>IBA</item>
        <item>Short</item>
        <item>Highball</item>
        <item>Tiki</item>
        <item>Shooter</item>
        <item>Classic</item>
        <item>Blended</item>
        <item>Sour</item>
        <item>Sweet</item>
        <item>Strong</item>
        <item>Easy</item>
        <item>Complex</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="app_name">Bartender</string>
    <string name="vodka">Vodka is a distilled beverage composed primarily of water and ethanol, sometimes with traces of impurities and flavorings. Traditionally, vodka is made by the distillation of fermented cereal grains or potatoes, though some modern brands use other substances, such as fruits or sugar.   Vodka is traditionally drunk neat (not mixed with any water, ice, or other mixer), though it is often served chilled in the vodka belt countries (Belarus, Estonia, Finland, Iceland, Latvia, Lithuania, Norway, Poland, Russia, Sweden, Ukraine). </string>
    <string name="gin">Gin is a liquor with some level of juniper flavor that’s bottled at at least 40 percent alcohol by volume. The U.S. government defines gin as a liquid “produced by distillation or mixing of spirits with juniper berries and other aromatics or extracts.”  Juniper, gin’s defining characteristic, tastes primarily like pine, but is also herbaceous and floral. Gin production dates back to the Dutch genever, a wine-based medicinal spirit. The English got a hold of genever during the 80 Years War and the 30 Years War in the 1600s, where it was referred to as “Dutch courage.”</string>
    <string name="rum">Rum is a distilled alcoholic beverage made from sugarcane byproducts, such as molasses, or directly from sugarcane juice, by a process of fermentation and distillation. The distillate, a clear liquid, is then usually aged in oak barrels. The majority of the world\'s rum production occurs in the Caribbean and Latin America. Rum is also produced in Scotland, Austria, Spain, Australia, New Zealand, Fiji, the Philippines, India, Reunion Island, Mauritius, South Africa, Taiwan, Thailand, Japan, the United States, and Canada. Rums are produced in various grades. Light rums are commonly used in cocktails, whereas "golden" and "dark" rums were typically consumed straight or neat, on the rocks, or used for cooking, but are now commonly consumed with mixers. Premium rums are also available, made to be consumed either straight or iced. Rum plays a part in the culture of most islands of the West Indies as well as in The Maritimes and Newfoundland. This beverage has famous associations with the Royal Navy (where it was mixed with water or beer to make grog) and piracy (where it was consumed as bumbo).</string>
    <string name="tequila">Tequila is a regionally specific distilled beverage and type of alcoholic drink made from the blue agave plant, primarily in the area surrounding the city of Tequila, 65 km (40 mi) northwest of Guadalajara, and in the highlands (Los Altos) of the central western Mexican state of Jalisco. Aside from differences in region of origin, tequila is a type of mezcal (and the regions of production of the two drinks are overlapping). The distinction in the method of production is that tequila must use only blue agave plants rather than any type of agave. Tequila is commonly served neat in Mexico and as a shot with salt and lime across the rest of the world. The red volcanic soil in the region around the city of Tequila is particularly well suited to the growing of the blue agave, and more than 300 million of the plants are harvested there each year. </string>
    <string name="whiskey">Whisky or whiskey is a type of distilled alcoholic beverage made from fermented grain mash. Various grains (which may be malted) are used for different varieties, including barley, corn (maize), rye, and wheat. Whisky is typically aged in wooden casks, generally made of charred white oak. Whisky is a strictly regulated spirit worldwide with many classes and types. The typical unifying characteristics of the different classes and types are the fermentation of grains, distillation, and aging in wooden barrels. </string>
    <string name="ale">Ale is a type of beer brewed using a warm fermentation method, resulting in a sweet, full-bodied and fruity taste. Historically, the term referred to a drink brewed without hops. As with most beers, ale typically has a bittering agent to balance the sweetness of the malt and act as a preservative. Ale was originally bittered with gruit, a mixture of herbs or spices boiled in the wort before fermentation. Later, hops replaced gruit as the bittering agent. Ale, along with bread, was an important source of nutrition in the medieval world, particularly small beer, also known as table beer or mild beer, which was highly nutritious, contained just enough alcohol to act as a preservative, and provided hydration without intoxicating effects.</string>
    <string name="amaretto">Amaretto (Italian for "a little bitter") is a sweet, almond-flavoured, Italian liqueur associated with Saronno, Italy. Various commercial brands are made from a base of apricot pits, almonds, or both. When served as a beverage, amaretto can be drunk by itself, used as an ingredient to create several popular mixed drinks, or added to coffee. Amaretto is also commonly used in culinary applications. The name amaretto originated as a diminutive of the Italian word amaro, meaning "bitter", which references the distinctive flavour lent by the mandorla amara (the bitter almond) or by the drupe kernel. However, the bitterness of amaretto tends to be mild, and sweeteners—and sometimes sweet almonds—enhance the flavour in the final products. </string>
    <string name="absinthe">Few other distilled spirits have lived the long hard, magical, mystical life of Absinthe. Years before the 18th Amendment, best known as Prohibition was ratified in the U.S. in 1919 this often misunderstood green spirit – Absinthe, La Fee verte or The Green Lady – was banned in 1912. The Absinthe ban was based on a belief that the green liquid inside the bottle was hallucinogenic. When the 21st Amendment ended Prohibition in 1933 the ban on Absinthe remained. In fact, that ban remained in effect until 95 years later when the TTB along with the FDA authorized the sale of Absinthe in the U.S.\nAbsinthe is produced much like gin. It’s a high-proof neutral spirit generally 110 to 144 proof and is infused with a blend of botanicals. It can be many botanicals but the three main herbs used in production of absinthe are Grande Wormwood, Green Anise and Sweet Fennel. Traditionally, the alcohol is infused a second time before bottling to intensify the flavor and create the signature green color. </string>
    <string name="anejo_rum">Anejo Rum is a golden blend of rich, aged rums with a mellow taste and rich aroma.</string>
    <string name="angostura_bitters">This name brand of bitters is said to contain over 40 ingredients — although few can know for sure, since the recipe, which was developed as medicine by Dr. Johann Siegert, physician to Simon Bolivar, in Venezuela in 1824, is a closely guarded secret. Unlike many other bitters, Angostura isn\'t a citrus blend, but rather contains water, vegetable flavoring extracts, and a bitter root called gentian. It is also 44.7 percent alcohol by volume, and, contrary to belief, doesn\'t contain Angostura bark.</string>
    <string name="aperol">An Italian aperitif made from gentian, rhubarb, and cinchona, Aperol is sometimes thought of as the little brother of Campari.  In 1919, Aperol was born. It gained popularity through the 1920s, and in the 1930s, it became a drink “for women and sportive people.” Advertisements around Italy marketed the drink as something to help the fitness conscious stay “lean and fit.” </string>
    <string name="applejack">Applejack is a strong apple-flavored alcoholic drink produced from apples, popular in the American colonial era. The name derives from "jacking", a term for "increasing" and specifically for "freeze distilling", the traditional method of producing the drink.</string>
    <string name="aquavit">Akvavit or aquavit is a distilled spirit that is principally produced in Scandinavia, where it has been produced since the 15th century. \nA neutral spirit distilled from grain or potato (much like vodka), aquavit is most commonly flavored with caraway as its dominant spice. Styles of aquavit vary and often include a range of other spices as well, such as dill, fennel, coriander, citrus and anise.</string>
    <string name="averna">Averna is a popular Italian bitter liqueur (classified as an amaro) that is still produced from the original 1868 recipe of natural ingredients. The herbs, roots, and citrus are allowed to infuse in the base liquor for two extended periods of time. What exactly is included in this herbal blend is a mystery (or secret) for the most part, but pomegranate and the essential oils of bitter lemons are included in the list.\nAverna is dark brown, thick, and is best described as being bittersweet. It is sweeter than many Amari and you will note hints of anise, citrus, juniper berries, myrtle, rosemary, and sage in the taste. </string>
    <string name="benedictine">In 1510, the Benedictine monk Don Bernardo Vincelli created the recipe for this French liqueur, which calls for 27 plants and spices. The three main ingredients are Angelica, Hyssop and Lemon Balm.  Only three people on Earth know the complete recipe for making the spirit.</string>
    <string name="bitters">Bitters are made by infusing a neutral spirit with any number of aromatics, including spices, tree bark, roots, seeds, fruits, etc. Since before the cocktail itself, bitters were originally developed and marketed for medicinal purposes, with ingredients generally thought to impart good health preserved in a neutral liquor. As with most marketing campaigns, health claims began to be a bit outlandish—restoring youthful vigor, curing malaria, e.g.—but thankfully for all involved, bitters eventually found their way from the medicine cabinet to the liquor cabinet.\nIn fact, they have such an established place in spirits that even if you’re not a cocktail drinker, you’ve probably heard of a few of the most popular types of bitters. There’s Peychaud’s, used in the Sazerac and developed in 1830 by Antoine Amedee Peychaud, a Haitian apothecary who settled in New Orleans. There’s Angostura, with their oversize label, found in everything from the Old Fashioned to hangover cures. And then, in a different class, orange bitters, clear orange-hued citrus bitters with a complex of lighter-spectrum flavors that vary from brand to brand.</string>
    <string name="blue_curacao">This variant of the orange liqueur curacao is most notable for, let\'s be honest, making drinks turn blue.</string>
    <string name="bourbon">What began as a way for dirt-poor early American farmers to scratch a living from their fields has become one of the world’s great drinks. Kentucky Straight Bourbon has survived temperance, Prohibition and war, all the time refining its character and now enjoying a long-awaited renaissance.\nBourbon\'s roots go back to the late 1700s, when westbound British, Irish and Scottish settlers started making whiskey in Kentucky. In 1964, the US Congress established federal regulations for producing the spirit. All American whiskeys are distilled from a fermented mash (mixture) of cereal grain and water without any coloring or flavoring additives. Unlike Scotch or cognac, American whiskey must by law be aged in new, charred oak barrels and no more than 160-proof (80% alcohol by volume).</string>
    <string name="brandy">Brandy (from brandywine, derived from Dutch brandewijn, gebrande wijn or "burned wine") is a spirit produced by distilling wine. Brandy generally contains 35 to 60 percent alcohol by volume (70 to 120 U.S. proof) and is typically taken as an after-dinner drink. Some brandies are aged in wooden casks, some are colored with caramel coloring to imitate the effect of aging, and others are produced using a combination of both aging and coloring. The term brandy also denotes liquors obtained from the wines of other fruits. Apples, cherries, plums, pears and peaches have all been distilled into what are called fruit brandies or eaux-de-vie.</string>
    <string name="cachaca">Cachaça is just beginning to make its mark worldwide. However, this New World spirit is hardly new. In 1532, the Portuguese moved sugar production to Brazil and distillation of the plant into cachaça began shortly thereafter. Today, cachaça is the most popular spirit in Brazil with thousands of brands in existence that range from the cheap and plentiful to the rare bottlings that cost hundreds of dollars. Just like whiskey and beer, many cachaça brands are part of a craft movement that is gaining momentum. Only few brands were exported historically, but even small-production, artisanal cachaça can be found on the world’s shelves today. Cachaça is made from cane juice pressed straight out of raw sugarcane stalks. The fresh juice is fermented and then distilled into the beloved Brazilian beverage. Some rums, usually labeled as Rhum Agricole, are made in the same way, earning cachaça the name “Brazilian rum” in certain places. The major difference between cachaça and common rum is in the juice: most rum is distilled from sugarcane juice that has been processed into molasses, which has a higher sugar content. This makes cachaça have a more grassy, herbaceous flavor than its relative.</string>
    <string name="calvados">Calvados is an apple brandy produced in Normandy, France, made by distilling cider into an eau-de-vie, then aging it in cask. In the same way wine is overwhelmingly made with vitis vinifera grapes, the cider used for Calvados is made with specific apple varieties. Tart, bitter and sweet apple varieties all make their way into the cider blend to help achieve the harmony that’s present in any well-made Calvados. Hundreds of different apples are approved in the region and law mandates that a percentage of every orchard be planted to local varieties. </string>
    <string name="campari">Campari is an aperitif and cocktail ingredient, fairly common in classic cocktail recipes and equally delicious on its own. Perhaps best known for its characteristically bright red color, it tastes bitter and herbal and is still made in Italy, where it originates.\nCampari’s inventor, Gaspare Campari, spend two decades making bitter aperitifs of various recipes, eventually creating the recipe we recognize today as Campari.</string>
    <string name="chambord">A French black raspberry liqueur, Chambord\'s recipe is fashioned after a liqueur made in the Loire valley in the late 1600s.  The drink is made from raspberries, blackberries, vanilla, citrus peel, honey, cognac, and herbs and spices.</string>
    <string name="soda_water">Although it’s used almost interchangeably with seltzer, club soda is a slightly different beast. While seltzer is plain carbonated water and nothing but, club soda usually has a few mineral-y ingredients mixed in for added flavor.  Both selzter and club soda are suitable mixers for highballs and other cocktails.</string>
    <string name="coffee_liqueur">Coffee liqueur combines two of many people’s favorite drinks: coffee and alcohol. Plenty of sugar is added to balance out the alcohol’s sharp taste, usually. While Kahlua is the most well-known and widely sold, it is hardly the only option available. There are several other commercially produced options, and you can even make your own coffee liqueur at home.</string>
    <string name="cognac">For the past three centuries, Cognac has been almost universally recognised as the finest of all the spirits that are distilled from grapes. It has many incomparable qualities: fruitiness, subtlety of bouquet, intensity, warmth and, above all, the complexity of the many thousands of styles and flavours from a (predominantly) single grape variety.</string>
    <string name="cointreau">Cointreau is an orange-flavoured triple sec liqueur produced in Saint-Barthélemy-d\'Anjou, France. It is consumed as an apéritif and digestif, and is a component of several well-known cocktails. </string>
    <string name="creme_de_cacao">Crème de Cacao is a sweet alcoholic cocoa bean flavored liqueur, often scented with a hint of vanilla. It is different from chocolate liqueur, which is usually sweeter and more syrupy. It comes in 2 varieties, dark and white. Commonly used in mocha martinis or coffee drinks, this sweet syrup may also be sued to pour over desserts and ice cream.</string>
    <string name="creme_de_cassis">Though it sounds like the kind of spirit you find stashed away in a dusty cabinet, crème de cassis deserves your attention. An essential component in the popular Kir and Kir Royale cocktails, the dark, elegant liqueur is made by infusing a neutral grain spirit with crushed blackcurrants. As a result, it has tart berry flavors and a rich, earthy profile, with a hint of spice.\nCommercial production of crème de cassis began over 150 years ago in Burgundy, France (“cassis” means “blackcurrant” in French). The nation’s distillers continue to produce some 16 million tons annually.</string>
    <string name="creme_de_menthe">Creme de menthe is a very sweet mint flavored liqueur. It come in two versions, green and white (clear). There is no noticeable flavor difference between the two. When a recipe calls for creme de menthe, the white variety is usually the correct one to use.</string>
    <string name="creme_de_violette">Made from a maceration of violets steeped in brandy with added sugars, Crème de Violette was produced in Europe as early as the beginning of the 19th century, in an era when people clamored for violet-scented candies and sweets. The liqueur was originally served with vermouth or even on its own, until Hugo Ensslin published the first recipe for the liqueur’s most famous iteration, the Aviation, in 1916. The perfumed, floral liqueur made somewhat regular appearances behind the bar—lending its novel color and flavor to Ensslin’s classic and other since-forgotten iterations such as the Blue Moon and Eagle’s Dream—until the ‘60s, when its major European producer shuttered its doors, making it nearly impossible to track down in the U.S.\nIn 2007, importer Haus Alpenz introduced the Rothman and Winter brand and brought the classic recipe back into production and the U.S. While the Aviation remains the primary drink in which you’ll find Crème de Violette, many bartenders have begun using it as an aromatic seasoner for any number of drinks.</string>
    <string name="curacao">"Curacao" liqueur refers to a liqueur with flavoring from oranges that grow on the island of Curacao, off the coast of Venezuela. These oranges are known as bitter oranges or Laraha oranges, with the botanical name Citrus aurantium var. curassuviensis.\nThese are a variety of sweet Seville oranges that changed in the arid island climate and are reputed to taste awful on their own, but the sun-dried peels of them are prized in making liqueur compared with traditional sweet oranges. Today, bitter oranges are still used in many liqueurs and some gins, though these are most often sourced from other regions including Haiti and Spain.</string>
    <string name="cynar">Cynar (pronounced CHEE-nar) is in the class of amari, a group of liqueurs famous for their stomach-soothing qualities and generally low booze content. Specifically, Cynar is a digestivo, an almost-medicinal Italian after-dinner drink. Like its fragrant famiglia, it\'s made by steeping herbs (13 in this case) in a neutral spirit. But what makes the spirit really stand out is its primary ingredient: artichokes.\nDon\'t let this hearty flavoring agent fool you. "Cynar is quite beguiling," says Dave Karraker, VP of marketing and communications for the American division of Gruppo Campari, Cynar\'s Milanese parent company. "You expect it to taste as dark and brooding as it looks, but are welcomed with a liqueur that is bright and mixes in a cocktail so well."</string>
    <string name="dark_rum">Rum is technically identified as a distilled beverage made from sugarcane byproducts or sugarcane juice. Dark rum, however, is seen as the purest expression of one of the most widely used sugarcane byproducts, molasses. The rum is then (generally) aged in oak barrels. Various styles have emerged, including the highly popular Demerara style, which was the sweet base for Navy rums widely consumed in the 1900s.</string>
    <string name="drambuie">Drambuie is a blend of aged Scotch, heather honey and herbs that has a sweet, but balanced flavor. Unsurprisingly, it mixes incredibly well with Scotch—the whisky-Drambuie cocktail Rusty Nail is a true classic—but the liqueur\'s own complexity means it\'s great to use whether Scotch is involved or not.</string>
    <string name="dry_vermouth">Vermouth is a fortified and aromatized wine. Basically: wine spiked with brandy, infused with herbs and spices, and sweetened. There are two main varieties: red (sweet) vermouth, which originally hails from Italy, and white (dry) vermouth, which first appeared in France. Wormwood, of absinthe fame, is dry vermouth’s hallmark ingredient.\nVermouth, like amaro, was originally marketed for medicinal purposes. It then went on to became a celebrated aperitif, served on its own or with a twist of citrus. Eventually, vermouth found its permanent home at the world’s bar when it became associated with some of history’s most iconic cocktails.</string>
    <string name="egg_white">Adding eggs to shaken drinks is a tradition that dates back more than a century. Besides novelty, the egg white gives your cocktail a rich, creamy texture and a beautiful foamy cap.\nUnpasteurized egg whites are basically odorless and tasteless, so their contribution is almost entirely textural. Just as in a mousse or meringue, drinks that call for an egg white also include citrus juice and some sort of sugar syrup along with the liquor and egg. Agitating this mixture creates luxurious foam. While this element solidifies in mousse or meringue, the foam remains somewhat liquefied in cocktails because of the additional ingredient—the liquor.</string>
    <string name="egg_yolk">Egg yolks are not often used alone in cocktails. You won\'t encounter many recipes that call for just the yolk; recipes that call for egg normally call for either the white alone or the whole egg. Unlike the use of just the white, though, the yolk does add a bit of flavor to a drink; in addition to helping to emulsify the other ingredients, a yolk makes a drink taste a little like eggnog.</string>
    <string name="elderflower">A French liqueur with an eau-de-vie base, St. Germain is an essential for the modern bar. It has the sweet, delicate flavor of elderflower and is fantastic in a great variety of cocktails. This is a very versatile spirit to mix with everything from Champagne and white wine to gin, vodka, and whiskey. There are many intriguing drink recipes you won\'t want to miss.</string>
    <string name="falernum">Some cocktail ingredients sound stranger than they are, and Velvet falernum falls right into this camp. But this Caribbean cocktail ingredient is easy to love. A staple of many tiki drinks, falernum comes either as a sugarcane syrup or as a liqueur, spiced with clove, lime, and generally ginger and almond.\nDue to its provenance (hailing from Barbados), falernum is most often paired with rum, and it’s a smart combination. But this intriguingly spiced, sweet-tart liqueur is quite versatile.</string>
    <string name="fernet">For the first-time fernet drinker, the popularity of booze that tastes like black licorice devoid of sugar might be confounding. The botanical, 80-proof fernet is no innocuous vodka. It is made from bitters and herbs, and though it goes down relatively smooth, the aftertaste kicks and lingers. It is, as almost everyone describes it, an acquired taste. \nIn Argentina, fernet is the liquor for all occasions. Grandparents swear by the herbal libation; the young heading out into the night mix fernet with cola and then order it en masse at bars and clubs; and no one would dare organize a barbecue, which are called asados in Argentina and are very regular affairs with friends or families, without fernet. It even earned a theme song in the \'90s: "Fernet con cola," about the bona fide national beverage by Argentine rock band Vilma Palma e Vampiros.</string>
    <string name="frangelico">Frangelico is a premium hazelnut liqueur. It is perfect on the rocks, in coffee or as the key to transforming standard drinks into intriguing cocktails. Crafted with wild Tonda Gentile hazelnuts from the Piedmont region of northern Italy, Frangelico presents a pronounced but delicate hazelnut flavor complemented by hints of vanilla and dark chocolate.</string>
    <string name="galliano">If you have any Galliano, the sweet, herbal Italian liqueur, lurking in your liquor cabinet, you\'ll know. Because there\'s no way this tall, skinny bottle and its Day-Glo yellow contents can ever get lost. Wildly popular back in the \'70s (yes, we know that\'s hardly an endorsement), Galliano has graced plenty of sub-par cocktails, but today\'s talented bartenders have started to redeem its reputation.\nMade from neutral alcohol steeped with a wide range of herbs and spices (juniper, anise, vanilla, and getting more obscure from there), Galliano has a distinctive vanilla sweetness that sets it apart from other herbal liqueurs, so when you\'re mixing with it, no simple syrup or other sweeteners are required. It\'s also full-throttle, at 42.5% ABV, a nudge higher than your standard spirit. It\’s boozy like Sambuca, rather than gentler like an amaro.</string>
    <string name="ginger_ale">Ginger beer is used in plenty of drinks, but ginger ale makes a great mixer as well.</string>
    <string name="ginger_beer">Spicy, spritzy ginger beer is always a great cocktail mixer to have on hand—and not just for a Dark n’ Stormy. As simple and delicious as that classic drink is, it’s certainly not the only boozy way to take advantage of ginger beer.</string>
    <string name="grand_marnier">An orange-scented, Cognac-based spirit that packs a boozy punch, Grand Marnier means a lot of things to a lot of people. A Gallic liqueur with immense history, it is equally at home in a Margarita or canonical French dessert.\nThe company was founded by Louis-Alexandre Marnier Lapostolle in 1880.  He had the then-revolutionary idea to pair Cognac with a then-exotic ingredient, oranges, in the Lapostolles’ laboratory years later. After 10 years of experimentation, Grand Marnier was born.</string>
    <string name="green_chartreuse">Distinguished by its bright green color and complex flavor, Green Chartreuse is a storied liqueur that\'s enjoying a modern-day comeback. Made by Carthusian Monks since 1737, it was originally concocted as an elixir of long life—but who knew it would turn out so much better?\nLike many European liqueurs, Green Chartreuse comes with its fair share of mystique. Made from a secret blend of 130 herbs, seeds, and spices, it has a curious and impalpable flavor: sweet yet spicy, herbaceous yet refreshing, with a much smoother finish than other mystery blends like Fernet Branca or Jagermeister. The result is a liqueur that\'s both endlessly versatile and eminently drinkable—the hardest-working addition to your liquor collection since your grandpappy\'s favorite scotch.</string>
    <string name="grenadine">Grenadine is a commonly used, non-alcoholic bar syrup, characterized by a flavor that is both tart and sweet, and by a deep red color. It is popular as an ingredient in cocktails, both for its flavor and to give a reddish/pink tint to mixed drinks.\nThe name grenadine originated from the French word grenade which means pomegranate, with pomme meaning apple and granate derived from the Italian word for seeds. Grenadine was originally prepared from pomegranate juice, sugar, and water.</string>
    <string name="irish_cream">Irish cream is a cream liqueur based on Irish whiskey, cream and other flavorings. It typically has an ABV level of 15 to 20% and is served on its own or in mixed drinks, most commonly Irish coffee.\nBaileys and Carolans are the most commonly available commercial versions.</string>
    <string name="irish_whiskey">The Irish style of whiskey is mostly triple-distilled, which makes it renowned for its smoothness.  It\'s also more likely to be made of a combination of grains, rather than just barley. The extra distillation probably has the biggest effect on the difference between the flavours of Scotch and Irish Whiskey. It gives Irish Whiskey a lighter flavour, and as mentioned before, makes the mouth feel smoother.</string>
    <string name="jagermeister">It’s been shamelessly frat-boyed and is most certainly imbibed in bar-dive darkness — you know, those nights when the air is deliciously musty, haunted with the bittersweet tang of future regret — but Jägermeister, made with 56 herbs and spices, is in fact a “digestif.” \nOn the digestif spectrum, Jäger is sweet. But it was born out of sour. Wilhelm Mast ran a vinegar company in Wolfenbüttel, Germany, slightly south and a bit west of Berlin. That’s where his son, Curt Mast, let his spirit for spirits blossom into the creation of Jägermeister, a liqueur flavored with a very secret recipe that melds spices, herbs, and a year of barrel-aging into something we should probably sip slowly but instead, for some reason, down prodigiously.</string>
    <string name="kummel">Dating back to 16th-century Holland, the clear liqueur is flavored with caraway seed, cumin, and fennel, making it taste a bit like liquid rye bread, with anise flavors and other spices lingering around the edges. It’s smooth but intensely savory. Cocktail geeks love it. First-timers…well, it depends.</string>
    <string name="lemon_juice">It wasn\'t that long ago that bartenders would reach for a suspect-looking bottle of store-bought lemon juice or sour mix any time a cocktail calling for citrus was ordered. The recent cocktail renaissance has brought back a much-needed appreciation for fresh juices.\nKeep fresh lemons on hand to juice as needed for cocktails if you can; if not, bottled juices will have to do.</string>
    <string name="lime_juice">It wasn\'t that long ago that bartenders would reach for a suspect-looking bottle of store-bought lime juice or sour mix any time a cocktail calling for citrus was ordered. The recent cocktail renaissance has brought back a much-needed appreciation for fresh juices.\nKeep fresh limes on hand to juice as needed for cocktails if you can; if not, bottled juices will have to do.</string>
    <string name="light_rum">Rum is a type of alcohol made from sugarcane or sugarcane by-products such as molasses or sugarcane syrup. Just like with agave in tequila, this sugar is then distilled into a liquid alcohol. Rum can be distilled to various strengths, but is typically higher than 40 percent alcohol by volume or 80 proof.\nLight, silver or white rum is aged for less time than other varieties. Directly after this spirit is distilled it is already clear. To make it into rum that can be sold, producers typically just filter the liquor until it\'s free from impurities and ready for a cocktail. Light rums have a sweet but subtle flavor and just as much alcohol by volume as darker rums. </string>
    <string name="lillet">Lillet Blanc is a white wine-based aperitif made in Bordeaux, France.  In 1872, Raymond and Paul Lillet, fine wines, liquors and spirits merchants, funded Maison Lillet. They created the first and only aperitif from Bordeaux, the Lillet (called Kina Lillet until the 1970s), a blend of wines and fruit macerations crafted in Podensac cellars.\nAfter the Second World War, the small family-run company decided to focus on exporting the brand to the US market. Lillet became the star drink of every trendy New York bar. The Anglo-Saxon market really took off in 1945 with the launch of Lillet Dry, which could be mixed with gin or served in cocktails and inspired the famous Vesper.</string>
    <string name="maraschino_liqueur">Never the star of the show, maraschino liqueur is usually relegated to the role of supporting player, yet a wide range of cocktails wouldn’t be the same without it. \nThe clear liqueur is made using the whole Marasca cherry (pits and all) in the distillation process, which yields a funky flavor profile that hints at fruity sweetness. Many find it a bit much when taken neat—it drinks more like a brusque eau de vie than a gentle liqueur. (Though Luxardo is the best-known brand, with its recognizable green glass bottle swathed in straw, Maraska and Lazzarroni can be spotted on shelves, too.)</string>
    <string name="mezcal">Mezcal, Mexico\’s wonderfully smoky contribution to the drinking world, works as a great base for cocktails or simply as a straight sipper.  The word “mezcal” comes from the Aztec word mexcalli, which combines metl (meaning maguey, aka agave) and ixcalli (meaning cooked). The literal translation of mezcal is “cooked agave.” \nMezcal gets its smoky taste and smell from the way agave breaks down before fermentation. The agave is placed in a pit dug into the ground and filled with hot coals, where it sits for two to three days, acquiring its signature smoky essence.\nContrary to popular belief, the worm in mezcal isn\'t a worm at all, it\'s actually a larva. There are two types of larvae that are often added to mezcal: white-and-gold or red. The white-and-gold larvae live in the agave root, and the red larvae reside in the long leaves of the plant. Despite the worms\’ prevalence among mezcal brands, the larvae are not necessary. And no, it won\'t make you hallucinate.</string>
    <string name="midori">Midori is the bright green liquor bottle that shines behind bars across the world. Its beauty extends inside to the sweet melon liqueur which bartenders use to create amazing green cocktails. In just a few decades, Midori has captivated drinkers and bartenders alike and it has transformed the cocktail scene.</string>
    <string name="orange_bitters">No matter the brand or recipe, the flavor of orange bitters comes primarily from the dried zest of bitter-orange peels. Usually, these are specified to be oranges from Seville or the West Indies (the latter of which are the same types of peel that are used in triple sec and curaçao).\nBy the end of the 1800s, orange bitters were prominent in cocktail recipes, but perhaps their most famous use was in the original dry martini.</string>
    <string name="orange_juice">If you want the best orange juice cocktails possible, squeeze the juice yourself. There are many fruit and citrus juicers available to fit any need and oranges are inexpensive year-round, so you cannot go wrong.\nOn the other hand, the reality is that you\'re not always going to take the time to squeeze the fresh orange juice. It is a world filled with convenience and there are some great bottles of orange juice available. In this case, do your best to choose an all-natural, not-from-concentrate juice.</string>
    <string name="orgeat">Orgeat (pronounced "or-zsa," like Zsa Zsa Gabor) is like liquid marzipan. While it\'s best known as a part of a good Mai Tai, this almond syrup is also an exotic substitute for simple syrup or grenadine in mixed drinks or a fun addition to pie fillings, milk shakes, and even coffee.</string>
    <string name="ouzo">Ouzo is not trying to lie to you about what it is. Assertively anise-flavored, grape-based, clear-until-it-turns-cloudy, ouzo is a distinctively flavorful, and distinctively Greek drink. Distilled from a grape base (called tsipoura) that’s flavored with herbs (wintergreen, mint, fennel) and anise and spices in copper stills to 96% ABV, it’s flavored assertively (the star is anise, with costars like fennel, coriander, cloves, cinnamon, and star anise. Served in small glasses, it has a funny habit of turning white when you add water—called the “louche” effect, due to the anise oil. It does not, however, lose any of its licorice potency.</string>
    <string name="pernod">Created in 1932 by Paul Ricard in response to the 1915 ban of the sale of absinthe, Pernod has a similar anise-flavored base, but is different in several key respects. First off, it\'s got no grand wormwood, the supposedly hallucinogenic herb that got absinthe banned in the first place. Second, it\'s flavored with star-anise, the fruit of a dried Chinese evergreen tree (you can buy it at the supermarket), rather than the true green anise used for absinthe. </string>
    <string name="peychaud_bitters">In the early 1800s Antonie Amedie Peychaud, an apothecary, gained fame in New Orleans not for the drugs he dispensed, but for the compounding of a liquid tonic called bitters. These bitters -- good for what ailed one, irrespective of malady -- gave an added zest to the potions of cognac brandy he served in his pharmacy. Cognac had long been a popular drink in the numerous coffee houses of New Orleans and presently customers began demanding their brandy spiked with a dash of the marvelous Peychaud\'s Bitters. The zest it gives drinks and food has given it an honored place in famous gourmet recipes the world over.</string>
    <string name="pisco">Want to start a fight between a Peruvian and a Chilean? Tell them that the other country makes better pisco. The national spirit of both nations, pisco has hotly disputed origins with each dismissing the other\’s pisco as a cheap imitation.\nPisco is a grape brandy, meaning that it\'s made from grapes that are fermented and then distilled. Unlike the French brandies Cognac and Armagnac, most pisco doesn\'t spend any time in a barrel, so it\'s a clear spirit, not a brown one.</string>
    <string name="port">Port: the fortified wine that has held a distinct, prestigious allure for over 400 years. Mainly known as an aperitif that is served neat, Port also has a storied history of being a main ingredient in cocktails. In the 17th century, British gentlemen and sea captains combined Port with sugar, water, and nutmeg to form the "sangaree" (the precursor to the modern day sangria). By the 18th century, Jerry Thomas famously mixed Port with an egg to create the "Port Wine Flip." Whether in a punch bowl or a silver Mint Julep cup, Port in cocktails used to be everywhere.\nThe uncanny compatibility of Port and spirits has a lot to do with how Port is made. In the days of sailing ships, transporting wine on a transcontinental voyage required that winemakers add alcohol in the form of spirits to make sure the wine survived the harsh conditions encountered during several months at sea. Typically, the added spirit increased the wine\'s alcohol level from 13 to 20%, and the resulting wine\'s hefty structure helped it keep very well for months in variable conditions and for many decades in a proper cellar. This is how fortified wines were born.\n</string>
    <string name="rye_whiskey">Rye whiskey is featured in a number of cocktail recipes, from timeless classics to modern creations that offer extraordinary, complex flavors. It\'s a versatile style of whiskey — rye\'s signature spice always lets you know it\'s there, no matter what you\'re mixing it with.</string>
    <string name="tuaca">Tuaca is a brand of liqueur produced by the Tuaca Liqueur Company of Louisville, Kentucky. Originally created for Lorenzo di Medici in the 15th century, the recipe was rediscovered by brothers-in-law Gaetano Tuoni and Giorgio Canepa in 1938 and given a name derived from their last names. \nTuaca has a base of Italian brandy, which is then infused with other spirits, sugar, citrus and vanilla. Tuaca is amber in color and moderately sweet, with strong flavors of citrus that are softened by vanilla.</string>
    <string name="sloe_gin">Sloe Gin is a fruit based liqueur based on gin, made using sloe, sometimes called blackthorn, berries. Sloes are a relative of the plum, and are indigenous to Europe and Asia. Sloe gin has a unique fruity berry flavor, initially mildly sweet turning to a lingering tart and slightly bitter finish.\nThe traditional method of making sloe gin is to harvest ripe sloes, prick them all over and put them in a clean Mason jar. Sugar and spices are added before topping up with gin. The jar is then turned every day for two weeks, then less frequently, until the liquid is ruby red in color, which usually takes three or four months. The liqueur is then decanted off the fruit and spices, clarified, and bottled. Homemade sloe gin typically has an almond aroma due to the extraction from the sloe pits.</string>


    <string name="oldfashioned">The Old Fashioned is one of the most venerable of cocktails, predating not only the motorcar but the presidency of Abe Lincoln. All it takes is serving whiskey, sugar, bitters and, if you like, a cherry or orange garnish on the rocks. Properly made, it\'s strong but not too strong, sweet but not too sweet, and, most importantly, it\'s dead-simple and absolutely delicious.\nThe best bitters for an Old Fashioned are up for debate, but Angostura is classic for a reason, while Fee Brothers offer a welcome alternative.</string>
    <string name="mojito">To many people, the Mojito represents the perfect rum cocktail. The origins of the drink can be traced back to Cuba and the 16th-century Cuban cocktail El Draque, named for Sir Francis Drake.\nAppropriately, almost all of the ingredients in the Mojito are indigenous to Cuba. Rum, lime, mint and sugar (derived from cane juice) are mixed with soda water to create a refreshing classic cocktail.\nThe Mojito is traditionally served over ice in a highball glass and often associated with summer. Like your cocktails with literary references? You\’re in luck. The Mojito is said to have been a favorite of Ernest Hemingway.</string>
    <string name="longislandicedtea">On paper, the Long Island Iced Tea is one hot mess of a drink. Four different—and disparate—spirits slugging it out in a single glass, along with triple sec, lemon juice and cola? The recipe reads more like a frat house hazing than one of the world’s most popular cocktails. And yet, somehow, it works.\nThat’s because the Long Island Iced Tea succeeds where so many of today’s refined cocktails fall short: It’s boozy AF—more than four ounces of alcohol against less than half that amount in mixers. Unless you’re a sailor on shore leave, that’s a red-flag ratio rife with morning-after consequences. It’s also precisely what a person needs every now and then.\nBest then not to intellectualize the Long Island Iced Tea and simply love it for what it is: an easy-gulping, one-and-done stiffy. If you\’re looking to tame your tea a bit, pull back the boozy parts from three-quarter ounce to half-ounce, and lean in on the cola. The good people of Long Island won\’t be offended.</string>
    <string name="negroni">Easy to make and refreshingly bitter, the Negroni is said to have been invented in Florence by a dauntless Italian count who demanded that the bartender replace the club soda in his Americano with gin. It was a substitution that launched a thousand riffs.\nIn its hundred-year history, few cocktails have encouraged more frenzied experimentation than the beloved Negroni. Its one-to-one-to-one recipe of gin, Campari and sweet vermouth has become the platform on which generations of drink mixers have left their thumbprint.\nBut how do you mix the perfect version? Start by selecting the right base materials. The key to a great Negroni is finding a gin-vermouth pairing that complements, rather than overpowers, the bitter, bold flavors of Campari. Once you zero in on a winning trio, write it down, memorize it, and request it at your favorite bar. You’ll make the count proud.</string>
    <string name="whiskysour">Spirit, sugar, citrus—the original big three—come together in the Whiskey Sour, whose history stretches back to the Lincoln administration. Few drinks in the cocktail canon are as quick to satisfy and endlessly mutable as the Whiskey Sour. Add a flourish to any component, and you have your own personal spin on the classic. We like our Whiskey Sour thickened with egg white and a few dashes of aromatic bitters for a complementary spice note.</string>
    <string name="martini">You could stumble down a very deep, very dark rabbit hole trying to determine who mixed the world’s first Martini. Was it a California prospector during the 1849 Gold Rush or the barman at a flossy New York City hotel 50 years later? Both stories hold water. Neither will leave you feeling as blissful and content as a well-made Dry Martini.\nStart with a good London-style gin. From there, add a little (not too much!) dry vermouth and dash of orange bitters. And despite the prissy demands of a certain fictional British spy, stir (don’t shake!) the hell out of it with ice and strain it into a glass named after the cocktail itself. Twist a lemon peel, and there you have it, a Dry Martini. It’s a drink worth getting to the bottom of.</string>
    <string name="daiquiri">No drink has suffered more abuse than the Daiquiri. In the roughly 130 years since its inception, the granddaddy of rum cocktails has gone from the pride of Havana to an unloved extra on the back of a Señor Frog’s table tent. Even today, as the craft cocktail movement reaches full tilt, most people too often associate the Daiquiri with adult slushies, the stuff of spring break blackouts and mind-splitting hangovers.\nBut in its purest form, the Daiquiri is simple and sublime, a delicate blend of rum’s sweetness with the raw freshness of sugar and lime juice. Whole lives have been dedicated to balancing the three. That each ingredient should be of the highest quality goes without saying, though even then the Daiquiri can throw you a curve. Choose a too-sweet rum, and you’re sipping liquid candy; overdo the citrus, and the cocktail drowns in a puckering pool of acidity.</string>
    <string name="margarita">Tequila, orange liqueur, lime: The perfect margarita is all about fresh, crisp flavors. After testing all the ratios, this is the one we reach for.\nA good quality tequila needs no sugar to balance the acidity of lime juice beyond triple sec.</string>
    <string name="manhattan">The Manhattan was the most famous cocktail in the world shortly after it was invented in New York City’s Manhattan Club, some time around 1880 (as the story goes). Over the years, the whiskey classic has dipped in and out of fashion before finding its footing as one of the cornerstones of the craft cocktail renaissance.\nAmazingly, the drink that socialites tipped to their lips in the 19th century looks and tastes pretty much the same as the one served today at any decent cocktail bar. The Manhattan’s mix of American whiskey and Italian vermouth, perked up with a few dashes of aromatic bitters, is timeless and tasty—the very definition of what a cocktail should be.\nEarly versions call for rye, with its spicier, edgier profile. Purists claim that it’s not a Manhattan without it, but who has ever had fun drinking with a purist? We find that bourbon creates a beautiful, if mellower, drink. And while Angostura bitters are a must in any variation, a single dash of orange bitters helps brighten the cocktail’s edges, bringing the whiskey and vermouth together seamlessly.</string>
    <string name="moscowmule">This spicy vodka and ginger cocktail bites back. The Moscow Mule marries the clear spirit with ginger for a spicy kick. Lime adds a citrusy touch for a taste that will keep you coming back for more.\nThis cocktail traditionally comes in a copper mug, but feel free even if you don\'t have one.</string>
    <string name="alabamaslammer">The Alabama Slammer might just be the most ’70s of the bright and fruity 1970s cocktails. Its base blend of amaretto, sloe gin and SoCo stands in total defiance of what one would expect from a staunch Southern sipper. Yet the drink looms large below the Mason-Dixon line and beyond.\nSaid to have been born at the University of Alabama, the Slammer is a go-to at Crimson Tide tailgates, where’s it’s often served as a shot. And slamming one back certainly gets the point across. The nutty, herbal notes, backed by baking spices and citrus, come through loud and clear in a single bite.\nBut to truly appreciate the schizophrenia of the Alabama Slammer, mix it in a tall glass with lots of ice and freshly squeezed orange juice, and allow the mix to dilute for a minute or two. The flavors will loosen up and unfold at a leisurely pace, leaving you with a mellower, more Southern-tasting drink.</string>
    <string name="alaska">This gin cocktail, made with Yellow Chartreuse and orange bitters, “dances between spirit-driven and citrus-forward,” according to Keli Rivers of San Francisco’s Whitechapel. “It’s good, moving from one side of the spectrum to the other.”</string>
    <string name="alexander">The Brandy Alexander is a luxurious, creamy cocktail that has been popular throughout the 20th century. It is a brandy version of the gin-based Alexander cocktail and, honestly, brandy does make the better Alexander.</string>
    <string name="algonquin">Some of New York’s greatest writers (and drinkers) once sat at the Algonquin Hotel’s Round Table on 44th Street. Among the wisecracking guests at this literary luncheon were Harpo Marx, Robert Benchley and the martini-loving Dorothy Parker. It’s titillating to assume that with such large and mischievous personalities gathered in one room, even during Prohibition, a flask or two was always present. The hotel was long dry before the Temperance movement, owing to its puritanical owner Frank Case, but it didn’t stop the Algonquin Hotel from later christening a few house cocktails including this American jumble of spicy rye, dry vermouth and sweet pineapple. </string>
    <string name="allies">This drink was created during WWI and is named after the alliance between England, Russia, and France. It incorporates a spirit from each of the countries and is a fantastic riff off a classic martini.</string>
    <string name="amarettorose">Drinks involving amaretto, like the B-52, are usually among the sweetest treats in the cocktail world. This drink is a little bit of an exception, as the club soda mellows dilutes the effect and the lime contrasts sharply with the amaretto’s sweetness.</string>
    <string name="applecar">A delicious apple-themed variant of the classic Sidecar.</string>
    <string name="arthurtompkins">Arthur S. Tompkins was a justice of the New York State Supreme Court in the early 20th century; we can only assume this tasty pairing was named for him.</string>
    <string name="artillery">We owe this classic southern cocktail to the Chatham Artillery, Georgia\'s oldest military unit. The fine folks of Savannah have been mixing up this potent potable since at least the late 1700s. Legend has it that sometime around 1791, George Washington came to visit the Chatham Artillery on short notice. In keeping with their southern hospitality, the artillery members and their wives threw together what they had on hand and created this punch, which they then served at a ball in the president\'s honor. The punch was a hit and became a southern tradition, often being mixed in horse buckets when served in larger quantities. </string>
    <string name="balmoral">Invented at the historic Balmoral bar in Edinburgh, Scotland.</string>
    <string name="bermudahighball">A twist on the basic Highball, this refreshing drink is for those moments when you just want to disappear.</string>
    <string name="blackrussian">It takes a good drink to survive a Moscow winter. This recipe renders a fairly dry version of the drink. You can use more Kahlúa and less vodka to make a sweeter version.</string>
    <string name="blackthorn">This Irish-whiskey Manhattan has a subtle anise note.  For even more subtlety, use the absinthe to rinse the glass before filling with the drink, instead of adding it to the mixture.</string>
    <string name="bloodymary">This classic Bloody Mary recipe probably dates back to the 1920s. Ever since then, bartenders have been working to improve it, and there are some fantastic variations out there. This is the simple, no-frills classic version of the recipe.</string>
    <string name="bobbyburns">Practice your couplets and quatrains while sipping this cocktail named for the Scottish poet.</string>
    <string name="caipirinha">The national cocktail of Brazil, this refreshing summer classic features Cachaca, a Brazilian liquor similar to rum.</string>
    <string name="casablanca">  As many memorable movies do especially ones that already contain numerous references to liquor and drinking, Casablanca spawned a variety of cocktail recipes in its honor.  </string>
    <string name="casinoroyale">The Casino Royale cocktail was probably named after the first James Bond novel, and it has the sort of ingredient list you expect from the drinks of the sixties.\nBecause the lemon and cherry are so well-balanced in this recipe, the flavor of your gin comes through strongly and it’s worth using a good one.</string>
    <string name="champagnecocktail">According to master mixologist Dale DeGroff, this is one of the few original cocktails that appeared in the first (1862) version of the seminal How to Mix Drinks by Jerry Thomas. The recipe has remained unchanged for 150 years.</string>
    <string name="chicagofizz">The Chicago Fizz is a classic mixed drink that is a rich, eye-opening fizz with dark rum and ruby port as the base. It is a fantastic blast from the past and a sophisticated sipping drink with a lot of style and flavor.\nAs the name indicates, the Chicago Fizz has its roots in the Windy City. Who created it or how it came to be is probably lost to history. We do know that sometime before Prohibition it traveled the country and was served in the bar at the Waldorf-Astoria. It had its brief fame and, though it is a great drink, quickly became an obscure cocktail found in only a handful of bar books.</string>
    <string name="ginfizz">Love the Tom Collins? Try its frothy, bubbly cousin, the Gin Fizz. The secret to creating the perfect creaminess and froth is to shake, shake, shake—and then shake some more.</string>
    <string name="kamikaze">The Kamikaze was designed to cut to the chase. Invented on an American naval base in Japan after World War II and made popular during the great reign of vodka of the 1970s and ’80s, the Kamikaze isn’t the kind of cocktail bartenders sit around contemplating in hushed, reverent tones.\nIn fact, it’s not really a cocktail at all. The combination of vodka, lime juice and orange liqueur is served ice-cold as a shot and consumed, more often than not, in less time than it takes to assemble.</string>
    <string name="lochlomond">The Loch Lomond is so named because it features Drambuie and scotch. The vermouth tends to bring out the black licorice aftertaste of the Drambuie. The overall flavor is complex and just a touch sweet.</string>
    <string name="londontown">The London Town cocktail blends gin with maraschino liqueur, and just a little bit of orange bitters to bring them together. The orange bitters and the citrus and herbal notes in the gin bring out the tart side of the cherry flavor.</string>
    <string name="maitai">The Mai Tai is perhaps the most famous Tiki cocktail for a good reason. Trader Vic’s is credited with inventing the drink, and the first person to try it was said to cry out “Mai Tai!” which means “the best—out of this world” in Tahitian. The Mai Tai took a star turn by earning a prominent role in the Elvis film Blue Hawaii.\nThe Mai Tai was created as a way to showcase the flavors of good-quality rum. It should never be neon-colored or overly sweet. A proper Mai Tai is a deep amber hue and allows the rum to shine through with the other ingredients. While some Mai Tai variants call for pineapple juice, this recipe omits it in favor of the more classic recipe favored by Martin Cate’s award-winning Tiki bar Smuggler’s Cove.</string>
    <string name="martinez">This classic recipe first appeared in O.H. Byron’s 1884 “Modern Bartenders’ Guide.”</string>
    <string name="pinklady">The Pink Lady was popular in the 1950s. It’s pink and opaque, so on first sight you might expect it to be cloyingly sweet, but it’s actually drier than most modern cocktails.</string>
    <string name="queencharlotte"> This one is named after Charlotte Amalie, the capital of the US Virgin Islands, which itself was named after Charlotte Amalie of Hesse-Kassel, queen consort to the Danish King Christian V. </string>
    <string name="sazerac">A close cousin to the Old Fashioned, the Sazerac has been kicking around in one form or another since 1840. In 2008, it was crowned the official cocktail of New Orleans, a designation more suited to marketers than drink mixers. The truth is the Sazerac has always belonged to the Crescent City.\nUp until the late 1800s, it was made with French brandy as a base—Sazerac de Forge et Fils, to be exact—before bartenders switched to rye, the spirit newly arriving by the barge-load down the Mississippi. A well-made Rye Sazerac is indeed a tasty thing, full of spice and depth.</string>
    <string name="sidecar">The Ritz Hotel in Paris claims to have created this cocktail in the early 20th century. The potent combination of Cognac and orange-flavored liqueur shaken until ice cold with lemon juice is a timeless classic.</string>
    <string name="tomcollins"> The Tom Collins is essentially a sparkling lemonade spiked with a healthy dose of the juniper spirit. While there is a debate which side of the pond this drink was born, this cocktail lives up to his classic status with every sip.</string>
    <string name="tuxedo">The drink’s name refers to the Tuxedo Park, a sort of early experiment in country club living established in 1886 about 35 miles from Jersey City. </string>
    <string name="vermouthcassis">The Vermouth Cassis is a very simple and light drink, ideal for those times you want something with just a touch of alcohol, but a whole lot of refreshment. The name says it all; it is a mix of dry vermouth and creme de cassis served over ice and topped with soda.</string>
    <string name="sexonthebeach">Sex on the Beach sports a provocative name for a harmless fruity cocktail. It’s easy to make and even easier to drink, so it’s perfect for your next tropical vacation or cocktail party.\nNo one can seem to agree on where the name Sex on the Beach originated, but many suggest the cocktail may have been invented when a bartender combined a Fuzzy Navel with a Cape Codder. The fruity sipper is served over ice in a Highball glass and garnished with an orange slice.</string>
    <string name="piscosour">The national cocktail of Chile and Peru, this drink may have evolved from the Pisco Punch, which was all the rage in San Francisco during the 1849 gold rush.</string>
    <string name="b52">Believed to have originated in the 1970s from a bartender and fan of the iconic band, the B-52 is a classic guilty pleasure armed with three liqueurs. Make this layered shooter in seconds and impress all your friends.</string>
    <string name="tequilasunrise">The Tequila Sunrise, with its bright striations of color, evokes a summer sunrise. This simple classic has only three ingredients—tequila, grenadine and orange juice—and is served unmixed to preserve the color of each layer.\nThe Tequila Sunrise was created by Bobby Lozoff and Billy Rice in Sausalito, Calif. The cocktail achieved notoriety after Mick Jagger began drinking it, and The Rolling Stones dubbed their 1972 tour “the cocaine and Tequila Sunrise tour.” The drink has been a part of the cocktail canon ever since.</string>
    <string name="vodkamartini">If you must.</string>
    <string name="aviation">A classic gin sipper dating back to the turn of the 20th century, the Aviation was all but forgotten until about a decade ago. That’s when its secret-weapon ingredient, crème de violette, reappeared on the American market. Today, the cocktail is distinguished by its purple-bluish hue and floral, citrus flavors. And to that we say, welcome back!</string>
    <string name="betweenthesheets">Add a little rum to the Sidecar and you get this provocatively named classic.</string>
    <string name="marypickford">Sweet but with a real kick, just like its namesake.</string>
    <string name="monkeygland">In his 1922 ABC of Mixing Cocktails book, Harry McElhone (owner of Harry\'s New York Bar in Paris) took credit for the invention of the Monkey Gland. He also claims that the name was inspired by the 1920s experiments of one Serge Voronoff.\nVoronoff was experimenting with various implants. The most famous of these was the grafting of monkey testicle tissue (or monkey glands) to human testicles.  Voronoff was well-known for this rather shocking technique and over time he received a considerable amount of ridicule for it and died in near obscurity in the 1950s.</string>
    <string name="whitelady">She may look delicate, but this is one strong woman.</string>
    <string name="cosmopolitan">The legendary Cosmopolitan is a simple cocktail with a big history. It reached its height of popularity in the 1990s, when the HBO show “Sex and the City” was at its peak. The pink-hued Martini was a favorite of the characters on the show.\nAccording to Gary Regan, the original Cosmopolitan was created by South Beach bartender Cheryl Cook. Eager to invent a new cocktail for the Martini glass, Cook riffed on the classic Kamikaze using a newly introduced citrus-flavored vodka plus a splash of cranberry juice.</string>
    <string name="frenchconnection">The simple two-ingredient French Connection is one of the best ways to enjoy a young cognac.</string>
    <string name="hemingway">The Hemingway daiquiri has arguably become the most popular variation of this classic rum cocktail, perhaps unseating the undisputed heavyweight champion of the 1990s, the frozen strawberry daiquiri.\nA prolific drinker, Hemingway likely had a number of cocktails named after him. Most had little in common with the legendary writer, but to connect a concoction with the original Most Interesting Man In The World was a good way to sell cocktails.\nWe don’t know if Hemingway ever drank his namesake cocktail at El Floridita. One of Hemingway’s go-to watering holes in Havana created the cocktail to appeal to casual drinkers and leverage the name of one of its most famous patrons.</string>
    <string name="horseneck">This American whiskey classic has only two ingredients.</string>
    <string name="mimosa">The ultimate brunch classic.</string>
    <string name="mintjulep">The Mint Julep is a bourbon cocktail best known for being the signature drink of the Kentucky Derby. But this easy-to-make refresher shouldn’t be reserved for only one day a year. This classic cocktail was created in the southern United States during the 18th century and is still a favorite today.\nThe Mint Julep is traditionally served in a Highball glass or silver Julep cup over crushed ice and garnished with mint. Since bourbon is the only liquid in the drink, you’ll want to use a high-quality bourbon you know you love.</string>
    <string name="rose">A sweet and romantic wine drink, the Rose cocktail was popular in 1920s Paris and was created by Johnny Mitta, barman at the Chatham Hotel.</string>
    <string name="frenchmartini">The French Martini is the drink that helped to kick off the flavored Martini craze of the ’90s. The cocktail was brought to prominence in NYC restauranteur Keith McNally’s Balthazar, where it appeared on the menu after being placed on the menu in one of his other establishments.\nIt’s sweet and creamy due to the pineapple juice and Chambord black raspberry liqueur. The primary spirit is vodka, though sometimes rum is used instead.</string>
    <string name="russianspringpunch">Adapted from a recipe by famed London mixologist Dick Bradsell, this bubbly single-portion punch can easily be scaled up in a punch bowl to serve larger groups.</string>
    <string name="vampiro">The original design of this traditional Mexican take on the Bloody Mary was a combination of tequila and a homemade sangrita, however the use of orange juice with tomato juice and spices in this cocktail recipe bring those together in the build itself. </string>
    <string name="vesper">The Vesper, also known as the Vesper Martini, was made famous by James Bond. The cocktail best known for being ordered “shaken not stirred” was invented by none other than Bond author Ian Fleming. The Vesper first appeared in his book “Casino Royale,” which was published in 1953 and gets its name from fictional double agent Vesper Lynd.\nWhen Bond orders the Vesper, it comes with strict instructions that must be followed by any who make it: “Three measures of Gordon’s, one of vodka, half a measure of Kina Lillet. Shake it very well until it’s ice-cold, then add a large thin slice of lemon peel. Got it?”</string>
    <string name="yellowbird">You don’t need to be Audubon to appreciate this tasty cocktail.</string>
    <string name="adamneve">Xavier Herit\’s biblically named drink is a nod to the forbidden fruit Adam and Eve couldn’t keep their curious paws off of. \nHerit bottles this cocktail for easy service at his New York City bar Wallflower, but you can serve it up in a coupe glass at home if you prefer.</string>
    <string name="addington">For true vermouth devotees comes this cocktail which is nothing but.</string>
    <string name="ginrickey">If you look at the gin rickey and think it\'s nothing but a gin and tonic without tonic\'s bittersweet bite, you\'d be mostly correct. Dismiss it as a G\+T wannabe, however, and you\'re missing out on one of the great joys of summer. Created in a Washington, D.C., bar called Shoemaker\'s during an especially brutal heat wave in the 1890s—before the advent of air conditioning, you\'ll note—the gin rickey is like an effervescent Frigidaire. Refreshingly bubbly and pleasantly bitter, this Gilded Age cooler demonstrates how your great-grandparents made it through the summer alive.</string>
    <string name="zombie">This tropical drink by legendary Donn Beach of Don the Beachcomber restaurant kicked off the Tiki craze.</string>
    <string name="lastword">The Last Word is a Prohibition-era cocktail that got its beginnings in the Detroit Athletic Club’s bar in the early 1920s. The drink was served at the bar throughout this period and was spread further afield by vaudeville performer Frank Fogarty – also known as the ‘Dublin Minstrel.’\nThis is a sweet and sharp drink with a pale green hue and a bite bigger than it’s bark. This little palate cleanser is rich and pungent. It is best suited to those who like a sharp kick to a drink and The Last Word should be the first thing you order the next time you fancy a sweet, citrus hit.</string>
    <string name="ginandtonic">The gin and tonic has a storied history that places it at the heart of the largest empire the world has ever known. Indeed, it is not too much of a stretch to say that the gin and tonic was as essential a weapon for the British Empire as the Gatling gun. No less an authority on imperial power than Winston Churchill once declared, “The gin and tonic has saved more Englishmen’s lives, and minds, than all the doctors in the Empire.”\n</string>
    <string name="peguclub">The Pegu Club is a gin-based cocktail that was the signature drink of Burma\'s Pegu Club. The club, named after a Burmese river, was located just outside Rangoon, and its members were senior government and military officials and prominent businessmen.\nThe Pegu Club is best served in a chilled glass and is considered a hot weather drink. Its taste is reminiscent of grapefruit and some bartenders will garnish it with a twist of grapefruit peel or slice of fresh grapefruit, although it is commonly served with a slice of lime to complement the lime juice in the drink.</string>
    <string name="corpsereviver2">The Corpse Reviver #2 is rightfully considered by many to be the best-tasting of the Corpse Reviver cocktails. It’s one of the staples at Chicago’s gin-focused bar Scofflaw, where bar manager Luke DeYoung calls it “perfectly balanced, refreshing yet still strong. It’s an iconic cocktail that won’t go out of fashion any time soon.”</string>
    <string name="boulevardier">Swap out the gin in a Negroni for rye whiskey and you get the delicious Boulevardier. It’s equally complex as its gin-based predecessor, but the whiskey adds warmth, making it perfect for autumn and winter drinking.</string>
    <string name="bijou">Crisp and herbaceous, the classic Bijou cocktail from the late 1800s blends gin with a bouquet of herbs and spice from Chartreuse and vermouth.</string>
    <string name="gimlet">The Gimlet is a gin-based cocktail that\'s been around since the Jazz Age, if not earlier. The recipe is quite simple, but there are multiple schools of thought on how to prepare it. Gin is always the base, but from there disputes arise. If you\'re using fresh lime juice, some simply syrup is in order. If you\'re using Rose\'s (which some insist you must), no added sugar is needed. Some traditional recipes call for a splash of soda, and others don\'t. It really comes down to personal preference. And if you don\'t like gin? Swap in vodka and you\'re good to go.</string>
    <string name="oatmealcookie">This drink -- which does in fact taste like its namesake -- was originally intended as a shot, but it works just fine as a proper adult-sized drink.</string>
    <string name="laverstoke"> A little more complex in its make-up, the Laverstoke cocktail – named after Bombay Sapphire\'s distillery – is sure to go down a treat this summer. It uses the sweet and herbal notes of Martini vermouth and offsets it with elderflower cordial (or St Germain, a punchy, flavoursome elderflower liqueur, if you\'d prefer), and tops it with ginger ale before adding a touch of ginger and mint for a fresh, lasting finish. The resulting cocktail is a little sweet, a little savoury, a little fiery, and completely delicious. </string>
    <string name="tipperary">Since Saint Patrick was of Gaelic descent, it seems appropriate to mix a little Chartreuse, courtesy of France’s Carthusian monks, into this cocktail that shares a name with a town in southern Ireland. </string>
    <string name="adonis">The Adonis cocktail dates back to the mid-1880s and was named in honor of the first Broadway musical to run for more than 500 performances. Simple and low in alcohol, it’s the perfect weeknight aperitif.</string>
    <string name="affinity">The Affinity Cocktail is an old-school style cocktail, with no fruity liqueurs or fancy herbs. It features two fearsome ounces of scotch, plus dry and sweet vermouth, so it’s technically a double.</string>
    <string name="vieuxcarre">The Vieux Carré was first stirred to life at New Orleans’ legendary Carousel Bar at Hotel Monteleone in the 1930s. Like so many classic cocktails from that city, the recipe represents the crosscurrents of America at the time: brandy and liqueur from France, Italian vermouth, rye whiskey from just up the Mississippi and Caribbean bitters. The Vieux Carré is at once boozy, sweet, bitter and smooth—in other words, New Orleans.</string>
    <string name="bloodnsand">The Blood and Sand is a classic scotch-based cocktail that has withstood the test of time. The recipe first appeared in 1930 in The Savoy Cocktail Book by Harry Craddock and has become a mainstay on bar menus ever since.\nIt gets its name from a 1922 bullfighter movie and points to its ingredients: The “blood” represents Heering cherry liqueur, and the “sand” is for the orange juice.\nThe key to the cocktail is to use a smooth scotch that’s not too smoky and freshly squeezed orange juice. So forget about your Islay scotches (for now), and avoid that carton of OJ in the fridge.</string>
    <string name="wardeight">The Ward Eight, a turn-of-the-20th-century concoction, is one of Boston’s major contributions to mixology.</string>
    <string name="baybreeze">The Bay Breeze is a simple mixed drink that brings a little pineapple into the popular mix of vodka and cranberry found in the Cape Codder. It is an easy, delicious, and refreshing drink that can be mixed up in a minute and is a popular recipe that every bartender should know.</string>
    <string name="aperol_spritz">There’s a reason the Aperol Spritz is making a comeback. It’s one of the most popular apéritifs in Italy, and it’s as tasty as it is refreshing. Low in alcohol, aromatic with citrus and slightly bitter, Aperol pairs perfectly with chilled prosecco. The Aperol Spritz is as easy to make as it is to drink, meaning it’s perfect for any time of day and any occasion. It doesn’t hurt that it has a gorgeous coral hue.\nMeeting friends for an after-work Spritz is a long-established Italian tradition and one that’s easily replicated anywhere.</string>
    <string name="sloeginfizz">The sloe gin fizz is a popular fruit cooler and a wonderful way to enjoy the sweet taste of a great sloe gin. This drink is easy to mix up and it is a nice cocktail for summer and spring days on the patio.\nIt is the perfect introductory cocktail for the sweet taste of sloe gin, which is seeing a comeback and used in a number of classic cocktails.</string>
    <string name="nutsandberries">A creamy dessert cocktail combining hazelnut and raspberry liqueurs.</string>

    <string name="make_stirice">Pour all ingredients into mixing glass with ice, stir well.\nStrain into glass.</string>
    <string name="make_shakeice">Shake all ingredients with ice, strain into glass and serve.</string>
    <string name="make_pourice">Pour all ingredients over ice in a glass.\nStir and serve.</string>
    <string name="make_mojito">Muddle mint leaves with sugar and lime juice.\nAdd a splash of soda water and fill with cracked ice.\nPour rum over, and top with soda water.</string>
    <string name="garnish_mojito">Lime wheel, mint leaf, or both.</string>
    <string name="make_oldfashioned">Place sugar in old fashioned glass and saturate with bitters.\nAdd a dash of water and muddle until dissolved.\nFill glass with ice and add whiskey.</string>
    <string name="garnish_oldfashioned">Orange twist, maraschino cherry, or both.</string>
    <string name="make_longislandicedtea">Combine all ingredients except cola and pour over ice in a highball glass.\nAdd a splash of cola for color.\nGarnish with lemon wheel.</string>
    <string name="garnish_lemonwheel">Lemon wheel.</string>
    <string name="garnish_limewheel">Lime wheel or wedge.</string>
    <string name="garnish_orangewheel">Orange wheel.</string>
    <string name="garnish_mint">Mint sprig.</string>
    <string name="garnish_bitters">Dash bitters onto top of drink.</string>
    <string name="garnish_orangetwist">Twist of orange peel (twist over glass to express oil, drop in glass).</string>
    <string name="garnish_lemontwist">Twist of lemon peel (twist over glass to express oil, drop in glass).</string>
    <string name="garnish_martini">Olive, or a twist of lemon peel (twist over glass to express oil).</string>
    <string name="garnish_margarita">Moisten outer rim and press upside-down into salt to salt the rim.  Garnish drink with lime wheel.</string>
    <string name="garnish_cherry">Maraschino cherry.</string>
    <string name="garnish_nutmeg">Sprinkle with nutmeg.</string>
    <string name="make_moscowmule">Combine vodka and ginger ale in a highball glass filled with ice.\nAdd lime juice and stir gently.\nServe in a copper mug.</string>
    <string name="garnish_none">none</string>
    <string name="garnish_apple">Apple slice.</string>
    <string name="garnish_strawberry">Strawberry slice.</string>
    <string name="make_amarettorose">Pour amaretto and lime juice over ice.\nTop with soda.</string>
    <string name="make_highball">Pour everything but soda over ice cubes in a glass.\nTop with soda and stir.</string>
    <string name="make_stirglass">Pour all ingredients into glass, stirring gently.</string>
    <string name="make_stirglassice">Pour all ingredients into glass with ice, stirring gently.</string>
    <string name="garnish_bloodymary">A celery stick, olive, or both are traditional.</string>
    <string name="make_bluelagoon">Pour vodka and curacao over ice in a highball glass.  Top with lemonade, but do not stir.</string>
    <string name="make_caipirinha">Place lime and sugar in an old-fashioned glass and muddle.  Fill glass with ice and add the Cachaca.</string>
    <string name="make_champagnecocktail">Dash bitters onto sugar cube and drop into champagne flute.\nAdd cognac, followed by gently pouring champagne.</string>
    <string name="make_fizz">Shake all ingredients except soda with ice.\nStrain into a highball glass over ice.\nTop with soda water.</string>
    <string name="make_cubalibre">Pour all ingredients over ice in a Collins or highball glass.</string>
    <string name="make_french75">Shake gin, sugar, and lemon juice with ice.\nStrain into a champagne flute.\nTop with sparkling wine.</string>
    <string name="make_ginandtonic">Pour gin and tonic water into a highball glass full of ice.\nStir well.</string>
    <string name="make_harveywallbanger">Stir the vodka and orange juice with ice in a highball glass, then float the Galliano on top.</string>
    <string name="make_sazerac">Rinse a chilled rocks glass with absinthe, discarding any excess.\nIn a mixing glass, muddle the sugar, water and bitters.\nAdd the whisky, fill with ice, and stir well.\nStrain into rocks glass.</string>
    <string name="make_tomcollins">Shake everything but the soda with ice.\nStrain into a collins glass.\nTop with soda.</string>
    <string name="make_b52">Layer the three spirits in a shotglass in the order listed.</string>
    <string name="make_tequilasunrise">Pour tequila over ice in a highball glass.\nAdd orange juice.\nFloat grenadine on top.  Do not mix!</string>
    <string name="make_kirroyale">Pour creme de cassis into champagne flute.\nTop with sparkling wine.</string>
    <string name="make_mimosa">Pour both chilled ingredients into a champagne flute.</string>
    <string name="make_mintjulep">Muddle mint and syrup in glass.\nAdd bourbon, and pack with crushed ice.\nStir until the cup is frosty.</string>
    <string name="make_blendice">Mix all ingredients with crushed ice in a blender until smooth.\nPour into chilled glass.</string>
    <string name="make_barracuda">Shake all but the sparkling wine with ice.\nStrain into ice filled glass.\nTop with sparkling wine.</string>
    <string name="make_vesper">Three measures of Gordon’s, one of vodka, half a measure of Kina Lillet. Shake it very well until it’s ice-cold, then add a large thin slice of lemon peel. Got it?</string>
    <string name="garnish_monkeygland">A monkey gland, if you have one.  Hopefully you don\'t, so just the drink straight up will do fine.</string>
</resources>
